(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-27T21:29:07.497268",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
イエー！
Yeah!
ワン、ツー、チェック、チェック、チェック、チェック！
One, two, check, check, check, check!
イエー、ハーハー、カモン、カモン、ヨー！
Yeah, ha-ha, come on, come on, yo!
ノー的用、ノー的用、ノー的用ですよ！
No-teki yo, No-teki yo, No-teki yo desu yo!
ジブラ、イエー！
Zeebra, yeah!
ドラゴンアッシュショー！カモン！
Dragon Ash show! Come on!
カモン、イエー！行くぞ、ヨー！
Come on, yeah! Let's go, yo!
Turn up radio そう 今日も聞こえるよ
Turn up radio, yeah, I can hear it today too
風に揺られ流れるStereo
The stereo flowing, swayed by the wind
肩で刻む軽快なRhythm
A light rhythm tapped by my shoulder
想いのっけて届けるよRhyme
Carrying my thoughts, delivering the rhyme
よく晴れた空の真下
Under the clear blue sky
僕らは遥かな未来目指しました
We aimed for the distant future
Master key 握り締め出発
Clutching the master key, we set off
雑踏の中 Kick down 一発
Kick down once in the bustle
今思う闘いの日々
The days of battle I think about now
感謝するごとに溢れ出す慈悲
Compassion overflowing with every gratitude
しのぎを削ったあの攻防戦
That battle where we wore each other down
今なお続くここは最前線
It's still continuing, this is the front line
父から得た揺るぎない誇り
The unwavering pride I got from my father
母がくれた大きないたわり
The great comfort my mother gave me
キミにもらう温かいぬくもり
The warm comfort I get from you
明日への糧に生き抜くために
To live as fuel for tomorrow
I got sound, I got feel, I got beautiful days
I got song, I got love, I got grateful days
I got it yeah
You makes me happy, when sky's gray
Darling, my darling
Thank you father, mother and my friend
俺は東京生まれ HIP HOP 育ち
I was born in Tokyo, raised on hip-hop
悪そうな奴は大体友達
Most bad boys are my friends
悪そうな奴と大体同じ
Pretty much the same as those bad boys
裏の道歩き見てきたこの街
Walking the back alleys, watching this city
渋谷 六本木 そう思春期
Shibuya, Roppongi, back in my teenage years
も早々にこれにぞっコンに
I fell completely in love with this early on
カバンなら置きっぱなしにしてきた高校に
Left my school bag behind back in high school
マジ親に迷惑かけた本当に
Seriously caused so much trouble for my parents
だが時は経ち今じゃ雑誌のカバー
But time has passed, and now I'm on magazine covers
そこらじゅうで幅きかす DON DADA
Throwing my weight around everywhere, the Don Dada
マイク掴んだらマジで No.1
When I grab the mic, I'm seriously No. 1
東京代表トップランカーだ
Representing Tokyo, a top-ranker
そうこの地この国に生を授かり
Blessed with life in this land, in this country
Jah に無敵のマイク預かり
Entrusted with an invincible mic by Jah
仲間たち親たちファンたちに今日も
To my friends, my parents, and my fans today as well,
感謝して進む荒れたオフロード
I give thanks as I push forward on this rough off-road
I got sound, I got feel, I got beautiful days
I got song, I got love, I got grateful days
I got it, yeah
You makes me happy, when sky's gray
You make me happy when the sky's gray
Darling, my darling
Thank you father, mother and my friend
日出ずる国に僕ら生まれ育ち
Born and raised in the Land of the Rising Sun
今こうして踏みしめる大地
Treading firmly on this ground now
常に開く新しい Page
Always opening a new page
旅に出ようそれぞれの Stage
Let's embark on a journey to our respective stages
ここに綴る喜びと感謝
Expressing joy and gratitude here
共に奏でる真の理解者
True understanding friends playing together
つつみ隠さず時代を描写
Depicting the era without hiding anything
Pressure はねのけて乱反射
Brushing off pressure, scattering reflections
注ぎ込もう溢れ出す感情
Let's pour in these overflowing emotions
いつの日にも絶やさない愛情
Love that will never fade, no matter the day
ひるむことなく飛び込む戦場
Diving into the battlefield without flinching
枯れることなく咲く百合の紋章
The crest of lilies blooming without ever withering
やさしい風抜け昼下がり
A gentle breeze blows through the early afternoon
虹ののぞいたこんな雨上がり
A rainbow peeking through after the rain like this
陽の光映した水たまり
Puddles reflecting the sunlight
日々の喜びここに賛美
Praising the everyday joy right here
この胸の高鳴りを
This throbbing inside my chest...
歌にのせて
...I'll carry through song
日々ここにあるもの
Everything that exists here every day...
この手に感じて
...I feel it in my hands
I got sound, I got feel, I got beautiful days
I got song, I got love, I got grateful days
I got it, yeah
You makes me happy, when sky's gray
You make me happy when the sky's gray
Darling, my darling
Thank you father, mother and my friend
ルパン！
Lupin!
ルパン・ザ・ファイヤー
[Title: Lupin the Fire]
Let me show you my everything
夢のこのファンタジー見てな
Check out this dreamlike fantasy
今こそ走る時なんだ
Now is the time to run
It's show time!
そこで見ててよワンマンショー
Watch me from right there, this one-man show
これぐらいの試練じゃ足りないよ
A trial of this level isn't nearly enough
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない
What I want isn't material things
I steal your heart
Listen!
僕は人生駆け上がる猛スピード
I sprint up life at top speed
まるでスキーの直滑降 核弾頭
Like downhill skiing, a nuclear warhead
決めたことには頑固
Stubborn about what I've decided
ゆっくり生きる術なんて知らない
I don't know how to live slowly
ここはステージ遠慮はいらない
This is the stage, no need to hold back
やることはやりますわ
I'll do what needs to be done
高みの山目指せ
Aim for the highest peak
Put your hands up in the air!
それを見つめる
Gazing at that
君はセクシー
You are sexy
甘くとろける
Melting sweetly
まるでチェルシー
Just like Chelsea
手櫛で髪掻きあげる様
Running fingers through your hair
僕にとっての女王様
My queen,
そんなあなたを今夜抱きしめる
Tonight I'll embrace you,
and 熱い唇をいただく
and press my hot lips against yours.
そして何よりも欲しいのよ
And more than anything, I want...
あなたの心 狂おしいほど
...your heart, to the point of madness.
It's a party night Dancin' with us
Everybody don't stop dance Let's go
just do it!
茨の道だろうが
Even if it's a thorny road,
凍てつく夜だろうが
or a freezing night,
不可能が可能になるさ
the impossible becomes possible,
君と二人で
with just the two of us.
だからそう だから
So yes, that's why,
誰も手にした事ないお宝もらう
I'll claim the treasure no one's ever laid hands on.
狙った獲物は逃がさない
I never let targeted prey escape,
それが何だろうと 大泥棒
no matter what it is, I'm the master thief.
先の先まで計算たてて
Calculating steps far into the future,
瞬時にひらめく名案
a brilliant idea flashes in an instant.
そして「あっ!」と思ったらもう居ない
And before you can say "Ah!", I'm already gone,
もはや芸術ばりの盗みの美
the fine art of thievery, practically high art.
Put your hands up in the air!
Let me show you my everything
夢のこのファンタジーを見てな
Let me show you my everything,
look at this dreamlike fantasy.
今こそ走る時なんだ
Now is the time to run!
It's show time!
そこで見でてよワンマンショー
Watch from right there, my one-man show.
これぐらいの試練じゃ足んないよ
A trial like this isn't nearly enough.
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない
What I want isn't material things...
I steal your heart
絶対に逃がさん！
I won't let you get away!
無駄な抵抗はやめて大人しくお縄につけ！
ルパーン！年貢の納め時だ！
Stop resisting and surrender quietly!
Lupin! Your time is up!
誰かが居ないと張り合えない
Without a rival, there's no thrill in competing.
相手が居てこそ間違いなく
Having an opponent is undeniably best.
身近にゃ素敵なライバル
A wonderful rival right nearby,
競い合い互いにハイになる
competing gets us both so pumped up.
ファイナルステージだ天王山
It's the final stage, the decisive battle!
お前と勝負の演奏さ
A performance showdown against you.
マジで今夜はサシで
どっちが勝っても文句はナシで
Seriously, tonight it's one-on-one,
no complaints no matter who wins.
Put your hands up in the air!
ワルサー使いこなす
Mastering the Walther,
僕はワルさ 曲がったこと嫌い
I'm a bad guy who hates crooked things,
プラスアルファ
plus a little extra.
ラップマスター ジェダイも目じゃない
A rap master, even a Jedi is no match.
しかし可愛い女にも目が無い
Yet, I also have a weak spot for pretty women.
Oh baby それは演技 or 本気
Oh baby, is that acting or for real?
僕は君に一本気
I'm purely devoted to you.
一本道走り続けます
I'll keep running down this straight road,
空へ飛ばす 今日から明日
flying into the sky, from today into tomorrow.
It's a party night Dancin' with us
Everybody don't stop dance Let's go
just do it!
茨の道だろうが
Even if it's a thorny road,
凍てつく夜だろうが
or a freezing night,
不可能が可能になるさ
the impossible becomes possible,
君と二人で
with just the two of us.
Let me show you my everything
夢のこのファンタジーを見てな
Let me show you my everything,
look at this dreamlike fantasy.
今こそ走る時なんだ
Now is the time to run!
It's show time!
そこで見でてよワンマンショー
Watch from right there, my one-man show.
これぐらいの試練じゃ足んないよ
A trial like this isn't nearly enough.
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない
What I want isn't material things...
あなたのハート
...it's your heart!
愛すべき 仲間や 家族がいる
Having beloved friends and family,
信念や プライドを 曲げずに 貫くべし!
stay true to your beliefs and pride without bending!
ルパンザファイヤー
Lupin the Fire!
Let me show you my everything
眩しい眼差しを受けて
Let me show you my everything,
basking in your dazzling gaze.
君のために今日を捨てるよ
For your sake, I'll cast today aside.
It's show time!
世界で一人の最愛の
To the one most beloved person in the world,
君自身に気持ち伝えたいよ
I want to convey my feelings directly to you.
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない
What I want isn't material things...
あなたのハート
...it's your heart!
普段はとぼけた三枚目
Usually acting like a silly clown,
やるときゃ誰より真剣で
when it counts, more serious than anyone.
頼りになるいざという時
Dependable when push comes to shove,
こうなりたい誰が見ても素敵
someone everyone admires, looking so cool.
知性備えたスーパーマン
An intelligent superman,
横にはお決まりスーパーウーマン
by his side, as always, a superwoman.
残り二小節ラストスパート
Two bars remaining, the final spurt!
憧れの男 Lupin The Third
The man everyone longs to be, Lupin the Third!
獲物は確かにいただいたぜ！
The loot has definitely been taken!
はい！ということで！
Alright! So!
『Great Days』と『ルパン・ザ・ファイヤー』
2曲続けて聴いていただきました！
You just heard "Great Days" and
"Lupin the Fire" performed back-to-back!
『Great Days』はですね、男性2人と女性1人の
For "Great Days", it's a song with two men
曲なんですけど、女性のところはね、
and one woman, and for the female part,
絶対AZKiちゃんがいいってことでAZKiちゃん。
I really wanted AZKi, so AZKi sang it.
で、ラップパートはもうノエルちゃんの顔しか
浮かばなかったのでノエルちゃんにお願いしました！
And for the rap part, I could only think of
Noel-chan's face, so I asked Noel-chan!
2人ともありがとー！
Thank you both so much!
でね、ルパンの映像が流れてみんなびっくりしたんじゃない？
And everyone must've been surprised when the Lupin video played, right?
ころねもびっくりした！
Korone was surprised too!
で、今日のハッシュタグは、
And today's hashtag is...
もうね、7周年だって！すごいよね！
It's already our 7th anniversary! Isn't that amazing?
この上のハッシュタグ「#戌神ころね7周年」で
With the hashtag above, "#戌神ころね7周年",
ぜひいっぱい呟いてください！
please tweet a lot!
スクショも大丈夫だよー！
Screenshots are totally okay, too!
ね、ここのステージ、
Hey, this stage...
なんか今日は違った感じだけど、
it feels a bit different today, but...
ここはどこなんでしょうか？
where could this place be?
どこ？
Where?
イヌバレー！
Inu Valley!
素敵！今日はイヌバレーから、
Wonderful! Today we're bringing you everything
すべてお送りしますのでよろしくお願いします！
from Inu Valley, so please enjoy!
って思ったんだけどさ、なんか画面小さくない？
Though I was thinking, isn't the screen kind of small?
って思ったよねリスナーさんもね。
I bet you listeners were thinking that too, right?
ころねもちょっと思ったので、ちょっとね、
Korone thought so too, so...
あ、ちょっと待って！
Ah, wait a second!
なんか枠が持ってる！枠が持ってる！
The borders are closing in! The borders are closing in!
やめて！ヤバいやばい！
Stop! Oh no, oh no!
縦長になっちゃうよこれ！
It's gonna become a vertical video!
ちょっと押して、今は令和なのでね、
Let me push it back. We're in the Reiwa era now,
画面を広く使いたいので、
so I want to use the screen widely!
あっち行け！
Go away!
もう一回あっち行け！
Go away again!
もう一回！
One more time!
オッケーオッケーオッケー！こっちは？
Okay, okay, okay! What about this side?
あっち行け！
Go away!
え、そんなにころねと居たいの？おいで。
Eh, you want to stay with Korone that badly? Come here.
ほんとに来るんじゃねえよ！ほんとに来んな！
Don't actually come over here! Don't actually come!
イキよ、早く！
Iki, hurry!
行った？
Did it go?
あ、行ったね。何だったんだろうね。
Ah, it's gone. I wonder what that was.
ということで...
So with that...
あ、なんか...
Ah, something...
なんか落ちてきたよ。
Something fell down!
花びらかな、これ。
Is this a petal?
あっちから降ってきた？
Did it fall from over there?
ちょっと行ってみよう！
Let's go check it out!
さくら
[Song: Sakura]
さくら舞い散る中に忘れた記憶と
Amidst the scattering cherry blossoms, forgotten memories and
君の声が戻ってくる
your voice come back to me.
吹き止まない春の風
The relentless spring wind blows,
あの頃のままで
just as it did back then.
君が風に舞う髪かき分けた時の
The faint scent when you brushed aside your hair
淡い香り戻ってくる
fluttering in the wind comes back to me.
二人約束した
Just like back then when
あの頃のままで
the two of us made that promise.
ヒュールリーラ ヒュールリーラ
Hyururiira, hyururiira...
さくら散り出す 思い出す 意味もなく
Cherry blossoms begin to fall, and I remember for no reason.
灯り出す あの頃また気になる
Lights turn on, and I find myself thinking about those days again.
変わらない香り 景色 風
The unchanged scent, scenery, and wind...
違うのは君がいないだけ
the only difference is that you're not here.
ここに立つと蘇る こみ上げる記憶 読み返す
Standing here, it all comes back; memories well up and I re-read them.
春風に舞う長い髪 たわいないことでまた騒いだり
Long hair fluttering in the spring wind, making a fuss over silly things,
さくら木の真下 語り明かした
talking all night right under the cherry blossom tree.
思い出は俺輝いた証だ
Those memories are proof that I once shone brightly.
さくら散る頃 出会い別れ
When cherry blossoms scatter, there are encounters and partings.
それでも ここまで変わらぬままで
Even so, up until now, this place remains unchanged.
咲かした芽 君離した手
The buds that bloomed, your hand that let go,
いつしか別れ交わしたね
before we knew it, we said our goodbyes.
さくら舞う季節に取り戻す
In the season of fluttering cherry blossoms, I'll take it back,
あの頃そして君呼び起こす
awakening those days and you.
花びら舞い散る 記憶舞い戻る
Petals scatter and fall, memories return.
気が付けばまたこの季節で
Before I knew it, this season came around again,
君との思い出に誘われ
beckoned by memories of you.
心の扉たたいた
I knocked on the door of my heart,
でも手をすり抜けた花びら
but the petals slipped right through my hands.
初めて分かった 俺若かった
I realized for the first time that I was young back then.
この場所来るまで分からなかったが
I didn't understand until I came to this place,
此処だけは今も何故
but why is it that only here, even now,
運命のように薫る風
the wind carries a scent like destiny?
暖かい陽の光がこぼれる
Warm sunlight spills down;
目を閉じればあの日に戻れる
if I close my eyes, I can return to that day.
いつしか君の面影は 消えてしまうよ何処かへ
Before I know it, your trace disappears somewhere.
あの日以来 景色変わらない
Ever since that day, the scenery hasn't changed.
散りゆく花びらは語らない
The falling petals say nothing.
さくらの下に響いた 君の声今はもう
Your voice that echoed beneath the cherry blossoms is no more.
さくら舞い散る中に忘れた記憶と
Amidst the scattering cherry blossoms, forgotten memories and
君の声が戻ってくる
your voice come back to me.
吹き止まない春の風
The relentless spring wind blows,
あの頃のままで
just as it did back then.
君が風に舞う髪かき分けた時の
The faint scent when you brushed aside your hair
淡い香り戻ってくる
fluttering in the wind comes back to me.
二人約束した
Just like back then when
あの頃のままで
the two of us made that promise.
ヒュールリーラ ヒュールリーラ
Hyururiira, hyururiira...
そっと僕の肩に
Softly onto my shoulder,
舞い落ちたひとひらの花びら
a single petal fell.
手に取り 目をつむれば君が傍にいる
Taking it in my hand and closing my eyes, you are right by my side.
さくら舞い散る中に忘れた記憶と
Amidst the scattering cherry blossoms, forgotten memories and
君の声が戻ってくる
your voice come back to me.
吹き止まない春の風
The relentless spring wind blows,
あの頃のままで
just as it did back then.
君が風に舞う髪かき分けた時の
The faint scent when you brushed aside your hair
淡い香り戻ってくる
fluttering in the wind comes back to me.
二人約束した
Just like back then when
あの頃のままで
the two of us made that promise.
ヒュールリーラ ヒュールリーラ
Hyururiira, hyururiira...
花びら舞い散る 記憶舞い戻る
Petals scatter and fall, memories return.
Petals dancing and scattering, memories dancing back.
花びら舞い散る 記憶舞い戻る
花びら舞い散る
Petals dancing and scattering.
タイムマシンにのって
[Title: Ride on Time Machine]
人はこれって時にどうしても
When people are in a pinch, no matter what,
「時間を戻せたら」とかいうね
they say things like, "If only I could turn back time."
でも誰も直せないよ 治せないんだな
But no one can fix it, no one can cure it.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's been like that since way back, so it can't be helped.
きっと先は深くて不安定
The path ahead is surely deep and uncertain,
でもお行儀よくっちゃつまんないね
but being well-behaved is no fun, is it?
タイムマシンに乗り込んで
Climb into the time machine
トラベラーになれたら
and if only I could become a traveler.
箱の中の猫を思っても
Even if I think about the cat in the box,
後悔だけが胸を焦がして
only regret scorches my chest,
いつもあの猜疑心が遮るんだわ
and that suspicion always gets in the way.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's been like that since way back, so it can't be helped.
きっと先は深くて不安定
The path ahead is surely deep and uncertain,
でもお行儀よくっちゃつまんないね
but being well-behaved is no fun, is it?
タイムマシンに乗り込んで
Climb into the time machine
トラベラーになれたら
and if only I could become a traveler.
どこをどうやってもね
No matter where or how you do it,
時間ってのは戻せない
you can't turn back time.
レンズ越し未来にめがけて
Aiming through the lens toward the future,
ピースサイン伝えてる 今の底いい調子
sending a peace sign, feeling good right now.
青春の1ページも
Even a single page of youth,
たったの1ページで
with just that single page,
自慢の人生のハイライトも 一夜きりのTweetのbuzzみたい
even the highlights of a proud life are like a one-night viral tweet.
君と出会った日のことを覚えてるよ
I remember the day I met you.
イヤフォン垂らしてこの曲をきいていたよ
With my earphones hanging down, I was listening to this song.
あれから数えて今日は何年目！？
Counting from back then, what year is it today!?
今じゃ足跡どこも残るから これは歌詞カード
Now footsteps leave traces everywhere, so this is a lyrics card.
載せず鍵かけておこう #%&$"=~
Let's lock it up without posting: #%&$"=~
ほらね、聴き取れない！！
See? You can't make it out!!
皆いつもくよくよ悩み
Everyone's always brooding and worrying,
締め切りに追われ歴史を作り
chased by deadlines, making history,
弱さを無理やりごまかし
forcibly masking their weaknesses.
君の芝生は緑 青じゃなくていい
Your lawn is green; it doesn't need to be blue.
アイドル撮られちゃった真冬の空に
An idol got caught under the midwinter sky,
政治家ぶれて プレっちゃった帰り道
a politician wavered and lost their way on the homebound road,
とうちゃんローン組んだ みはての先
Dad took out a loan, facing an endless horizon,
でも時は全部を流して
but time washes everything away.
人はこれって時にどうしても
When people are in a pinch, no matter what,
「時間を戻せたら」とかいうね
they say things like, "If only I could turn back time."
でも誰も直せないよ 治せないんだな
But no one can fix it, no one can cure it.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's been like that since way back, so it can't be helped.
きっと先は深くて不安定
The path ahead is surely deep and uncertain,
でもお行儀よくっちゃつまんないね
but being well-behaved is no fun, is it?
タイムマシンに乗り込んで
Climb into the time machine
トラベラーになれたら
and if only I could become a traveler.
俺ってやつはいつも気づいた時は手遅れ
A guy like me always realizes it when it's too late,
絵空事ばかりうつつ抜かして
getting absorbed in nothing but pipe dreams,
大事な人すら救えない
unable to save even the important people.
だからこんな歌で自分に言い聞かせて
So with a song like this, I tell myself:
あの時 あいつは多分気を使って
Back then, they were probably being considerate,
とくに顔色かえず 何もないふり
not changing expression, pretending nothing happened.
なんでいわないんだってムカついても
Even if I got annoyed, asking why they didn't say anything,
やさしさからきてたなら しょうがないね
if it came from kindness, it can't be helped.
願わくばディスコで親父と母さんが会った日に行きたいね
If possible, I'd like to go to the day my dad and mom met at the disco.
後ろのジョックスに酒 かけて息子じきじきにチャンス作ってやるぜ
I'll spill a drink on the jocks behind them and personally make a chance for my dad.
どんなでかい時計だってすべてさ 始まりはこんな小さい歯車
No matter how huge the clock, it all starts from a tiny gear like this.
細かいことはもういいや 疲れた
Forget the petty details, I'm tired of it.
別に怒ってないってさ 未来は
I'm not really angry, the future is...
人はこれって時にどうしても
When people are in a pinch, no matter what,
「時間を戻せたら」とかいうね
they say things like, "If only I could turn back time."
でも誰も直せないよ 治せないんだな
But no one can fix it, no one can cure it.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's been like that since way back, so it can't be helped.
きっと先は深くて不安定
The road ahead is surely deep and unstable,
でもお行儀よくちゃ つまんないね
but being well-behaved is no fun.
タイムマシンに乗り込んで
If I hop into a time machine
トラベラーになれたら
and become a traveler...
Forever Young
[Song: Forever Young]
シボレーのドアを蹴り開けて 街に飛び出した俺たち
Kicking open the Chevrolet door, we dashed out into the city.
暴力 酒に女 音楽 中指立てる大人の仮面に
Violence, booze, women, music—flipping off the masks of adults.
Oh さぁ踊ろう 「今日」という日を 生き急ぐメンバー
Oh, let's dance! Members living life in the fast lane today!
足りねえか? Little louder! 欲望渦巻く路上が現場
Not enough? A little louder! The street swirling with desire is our scene!
Yeah いつだってそうだろ ブルハ 尾崎 永ちゃんが教科書
Yeah, it's always been like that—Blue Hearts, Ozaki, E-chan were our textbooks.
くたばるまで格好つけてぇ 誓ったよあの放課後
Wanting to look cool until we drop, we swore to it that day after school.
俺らピーターパン 「またいつか」なんて言っちゃいかん
We're Peter Pans—don't go saying "maybe someday".
嘲笑っとる大人に言ってやらぁ 人生はたったの一回だ
Tell those mocking adults: You only live once!
胸の奥底 初期衝動
Deep within my chest, an initial impulse.
見て見ぬフリ No, No
Pretending not to see, no, no!
夢追い笑われ 傷だらけでギラつく My way
Laughed at for chasing dreams, covered in scars, glaring on my way!
Go on! You should know who we are
Forever Young
Hey! Just next to me from now 大切なことは魂の状態
Hey! Just next to me from now. What matters is the state of your soul!
Forever Young
Hey! It's your turn next time from here
「あの日始めれば良かった」
"I wish I had started back then."
その次の始めるべき時は今
The next best time to start is right now!
高笑いする都会の喧騒 ウケ狙いならば振り向けれんぞ
Loudly laughing urban clamor—if you're just fishing for laughs, I won't look back.
何連呼? 忘れろ? 夢流した便所 見下ろしてきやがる摩天楼
Calling out what? Forget it? The toilet where dreams washed away, skyscrapers looking down on us.
Oh まるで勝新みたく破天荒 伝説へとアテンド
Oh, unprecedented like Shintaro Katsu, attending us toward legend!
怖にゃあ怖にゃあってその程度
Scared? Scared? Is that all you've got?
捨てろ負け惜しみ 過去の栄光
Throw away sore excuses and past glory!
永遠なんぞはねぇて いつか天へ召され
There's no such thing as forever; someday we'll be called to heaven.
ペンで書き殴ったこの魂は 2PACみたく誰かの心を通過
This soul scribbled down with a pen, passing through someone's heart like 2Pac.
なぁ 何か忘れちゃねぇか 人生まるで映画 皆がエンターテイナー
Hey, haven't you forgotten something? Life is like a movie, everyone's an entertainer!
思い出せ 思想は現実化する 誰がHighway飛ばすBentayga
Remember, thoughts become reality! Who's speeding down the highway in a Bentayga?
胸の奥底 初期衝動
Deep within my chest, an initial impulse.
見て見ぬフリ No, No
Pretending not to see, no, no!
夢追い笑われ 傷だらけでギラつく My way
Laughed at for chasing dreams, covered in scars, glaring on my way!
Go on! You should know who we are
Forever Young
Hey! 俺達は今日だって 若気の至りのような夢を追いかけて来た
Hey! Even today, we've come chasing dreams born of youthful folly!
Forever Young
Hey! 変わるはずなんてない さぁ至ってやろうぜ!
Hey! There's no way we'd change! Come on, let's reach the peak!
今日は残された人生で一番若い日だろ
Today is the youngest day left in your life, isn't it?
半端な覚悟ならドブに捨てな (永遠)
Half-hearted resolve? Throw it in the gutter! (Forever)
往生際が悪い テメー笑い飛ばし 誇れ Better days
Laugh off your bad sportsmanship and take pride in better days!
まだ終わらない 終わらせやしない 燃え尽きるまで (永遠)
It's not over yet! Won't let it end until we burn out! (Forever)
まだ終わらない 終わらせやしない くたばるまで (永遠)
It's not over yet! Won't let it end until we drop dead! (Forever)
Forever Young
もう夢を追いかけ本気になった心は 自分の指図も受けない
A heart that became serious about chasing dreams takes orders from no one, not even oneself!
Forever Young
Hey! その思いから逃れられないなら 自ら向かうだけ
Hey! If you can't escape those feelings, all you can do is head straight toward them!
終わらせやしない 燃え尽きるまで (永遠)
Won't let it end until we burn out! (Forever)
まだ終わらない 終わらせやしない くたばるまで (永遠)
It's not over yet! Won't let it end until we drop dead! (Forever)
まだ終わらない まだ終わらない
It's not over yet! It's not over yet!
Forever Young
そう今日という日はお前に残された人生の一番若い日
Yeah, today is the youngest day left in your life!
マリン！ 来てくれてありがとう！
Marine! Thank you for coming!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
いや マンジこの「Forever Young」って曲をマリンと一緒に歌いたかったの！
Seriously, I really wanted to sing "Forever Young" with you, Marine!
あー、それはマリンがおばさんにならないように？
Ah, is that so Marine wouldn't become an old lady?
そう！ もうForeverヤングなんだよっていうね！
Exactly! Telling you "You're Forever Young"!
そうね、永遠にね！ ヤングな気持ちを... みんな Forever Young だよ！
That's right, forever! Keep a young heart... everyone is Forever Young!
フォーエバーヤング！
Forever Young!
で、マリン、今日はね、今日はね... 後ろ見て？
So Marine, today, you know... Look behind you!
演奏してくれた...
They played the music for us...
気まずいよ！
This is awkward!
今日演奏してくれたみんなが乗ってるよ。どの人と写真撮りたい？
Everyone who played for us today is into it! Who do you want to take a photo with?
え、そんな、1人だけみたいな... / 2人選んでいい、2人選んでいい！
Wait, picking just one person is... / You can pick two! You can pick two!
かわいそうだから選ばれなかった... / 2人選ぼう、2人！
It'd be sad for whoever isn't picked... / Let's pick two! Two!
ほら、もうコロネスキーが... / いや、マリンが選ぶんだよ。
Look, the Koroneskis are... / No, Marine is supposed to choose!
じゃあ、最初は... / あ、待って！映して、後ろ。
So, first off... / Ah, wait! Show the back.
みんな下向いて。
Everyone, look down.
ホソイヌさん。
Hosoinu-san.
かわいい！
So cute!
じゃあ、まずホソイヌと写真撮ろうか。 / かわいいよ、ホソイヌ。
Okay, let's take a photo with Hosoinu first. / Hosoinu is so cute.
こっちおいで、マリン。こっちね。 / はい、ホソイヌです。
Come over here, Marine. Right here. / Yes, this is Hosoinu.
えっと、ホソイヌはギターかな？ギターですか？ホソイヌちゃん。
Um, Hosoinu plays guitar, right? Are you on guitar, Hosoinu-chan?
ベロの色が... / かわいいね。 / 乾いてる、ベロ。
The color of his tongue... / It's cute. / His tongue is dry.
ベロの赤、ちょっと澄んでるんだけど。 / あ、本当だ。乾いてるね。 / あんまり触らないでね。
His tongue is red... wait, it's a bit dull. / Ah, true. It is dry. / Don't touch it too much.
ごめんね、いっぱい触って。
Sorry for touching it so much.
え、次誰がいい？ / あと1人、あと1人。
Who's next? / One more person, one more.
じゃあ、フトイヌ？ / フトイヌ。 / フトイヌね。
Then, Futoinu? / Futoinu. / Futoinu, then.
はい、フトイヌはドラムです！かわいいー！
Okay, Futoinu is on drums! So cute!
でかい！
He's huge!
かわいいね。
So cute.
あ、ベロの色がちょっと明るい。
Ah, his tongue color is a bit brighter.
ホソイヌより。
Than Hosoinu's.
撮った？みんな撮ったー？ / 撮った！ / かわいいー！
Did you get it? Did everyone get the photo? / Got it! / So cute!
オッケーだね。 / うん、オッケー。
All good then. / Yep, all good.
え、じゃあ最後さ、2人とも撮ろうよ、2人とも。 / あ、そうだね。2人とも撮ろう。
Hey, at the end, let's take one with both of us! / Ah, right. Let's take one with both of us.
ごめん、キャプテン。
Sorry, Captain.
え？
Huh?
ちょっと...
Wait...
あ、ごめんごめん！やっぱりとりで撮りたいみたいだから... / あ、やっぱりね。
Ah, sorry, sorry! Looks like they want to save the best for last after all... / Ah, of course.
コロネスキーともね、撮りますか。
Shall we take one with Koroneski too?
コロネスキー、ころさん好き？好き？ころさん好き？
Koroneski, do you like Koro-san? Do you like her? Do you like Koro-san?
あ、よかった。え、マリンも好き？ / 間に入ろう。
Ah, good. Wait, do you like Marine too? / I'll step in between.
なんでさー！コロネスキーなのに、ころさんの隣に立てない気分どう？
Why?! How does it feel to be a Koroneski and not be able to stand next to Koro-san?
嬉しい？マリンが隣で。
Are you happy that Marine is next to you?
嬉しくない？本当は好きなんでしょ？
You're not happy? You actually like her, don't you?
お前やめろよ！ / ダメ、もうダメ。帰るよ。
Cut it out! / No way, that's enough. I'm going back.
帰るよ、もう。はい、帰ろう。
I'm going back. Okay, let me head back.
はい、今日はね、バンドメンバーがいましたけれどもですね... / ええ。
Alright, today we had our band members with us, but... / Yeah.
はい。え、マリンとも最後撮りたい！ / あ、撮ろう撮ろう！せっかくね。
Yep. Ah, I want to take a photo with Marine at the end too! / Ah, let's do it! Since we're here.
Forever Youngだから、今日は。
Because today is 'Forever Young'.
マイク... マイク間違っちゃってるけどさ。
Microphone... Your mic is facing the wrong way, though.
マイクね。うん、いいよいいよ。
The mic, yeah. Yeah, it's fine, it's fine.
でかい声で喋れば拾うから！
As long as you speak loudly, it'll pick it up!
撮れたー？
Did you get it?
いけてる？ / フトイヌ...
Is it good? / Futoinu...
中心として... / いい顔撮れたね。
As the center... / Got a great face captured!
ありがとう、マリン！ / ありがとう！
Thank you, Marine! / Thank you!
これね、ちょっと次の曲があるから行くけど... / あ、次の曲。
Well, I have the next song coming up, so I have to go, but... / Ah, the next song.
1人で帰れる？ / お、え、え、そんな... あ、うん、大丈夫。大丈夫大丈夫。
Can you head back by yourself? / Oh, wait... Ah, yeah, I'm fine. I'm fine, I'm fine.
じゃあ、バンドメンバーのことよろしく。 / え？
Alright, take care of the band members for me! / Huh?
じゃあマリン、バイバーイ！ / え、よろしくって何によろしく...
Bye-bye, Marine! / Wait, what do you mean take care of them...
どんなムードこれ... あ、え？
What kind of mood is this... Ah, wait?
あ、みんな... あ、あえ？そしてみんな！次の曲だよ！
Ah, everyone... Ah, wait? And everyone, it's time for the next song!
のびしろ
Room to grow...
サボり方とか 甘え方とか 逃げ方とか 言い訳の仕方とか
Knowing how to slack off, how to depend on others, how to run away, how to make excuses...
やっと覚えて来た 身につけて来た 柔らかい頭
I've finally learned it, acquired it—a flexible mind.
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方 腹の据え方 良い年のこき方
How to look cool, how to get carried away, how to brace myself, how to act my age...
脂乗りに乗った 濁った目した だらしナイ身体
In my prime, with cloudy eyes, and a sloppy body.
嫌われ方や 慕われ方や 叱り方とか 綺麗なぶつかり方
How to be hated, how to be liked, how to scold, and how to clash gracefully...
もっと覚えたい事が山のようにある
There are still mountains of things I want to learn.
のびしろしかないわ
I've got nothing but room to grow.
俺らまだのびしろしかないわ
We've still got nothing but room to grow.
悪者扱いして来た街で
In the town that treated me like a villain,
悪者扱いして来たオトナへ
To the adults who treated me like a villain,
変わりゆく俺 鏡の中へ
My changing self, into the mirror,
尋ねても答えない yeah yeah yeah
Even if I ask, it won't answer, yeah yeah yeah.
去る者は追わない 引くとこ引いて
I don't chase those who leave, pulling back when I should,
丸く収めたり 軽くいなして
Smoothing things over or lightly parrying,
鏡の中でわろてるお前
You, laughing in the mirror,
括れやしなかったたったの三文字で
Couldn't be bound by just three simple words.
日々重くなる足取りで
With footsteps growing heavier every day,
自分の歩幅で闊歩してる
Stride along at your own pace.
カマすとこカマす まかすとこまかす
Show off where you show off, leave things where you leave them,
割と適当な段取りで
With a fairly casual plan,
やっと分かって来たかも
Maybe I've finally figured out
このポンコツの操縦の仕方
How to control this piece of junk.
19の時の「ついに来たか」より
More than the "It's finally here" back when I was 19,
もっと清々しい気持ち
A much more refreshing feeling,
隅田川にかかる
Spanning over the Sumida River,
勝鬨橋を渡る
Crossing the Kachidoki Bridge,
左手にスカイツリー
Skytree on my left hand,
右手に東京タワー 俺はその真ん中
Tokyo Tower on my right hand, and I'm right in the middle.
サボり方とか 甘え方とか 逃げ方とか 言い訳の仕方とか
Knowing how to slack off, how to depend on others, how to run away, how to make excuses...
やっと覚えて来た 身につけて来た 柔らかい頭
I've finally learned it, acquired it—a flexible mind.
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方...
How to look cool, how to get carried away...
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方 腹の据え方 良い年のこき方
How to act cool, how to get carried away, how to settle down, how to age gracefully,
脂の乗った 濁った目をした だらし無かった
In my prime, with muddy eyes, I was so sloppy.
幸せの体感速度は
The perceived speed of happiness...
早く良くなるばかり
...only keeps getting faster.
傷が癒えていく速度は
The speed at which wounds heal...
遅くなるばかり
...only keeps getting slower.
他人に期待をしないのが 今の俺の強み
Not expecting anything from others is my strength now.
手負いでも進める距離なら
If it's a distance I can cover even when wounded...
伊達や猥雑 身の程を知るほどに
Knowing my limits all the more,
胸を張り いつも通り
Pushing out my chest, just like always,
でも時にしたたかに背伸び
But sometimes slyly stretching beyond my reach,
やっと「大人気ない」ができる歳
Finally at an age where I can be "immature",
小さな枠組み ただの数字 縛られずに
Unbound by small frameworks or mere numbers.
でも腹くくり あの日の俺が立ち止まる
But bracing myself, the me from that day comes to a halt...
ほどにデカくそびえ立つ
...in front of something towering so huge,
隅田川にかかる 勝鬨橋を渡る
Crossing Kachidoki Bridge over the Sumida River.
重なるスカイツリー
Overlapping Tokyo Skytree,
東京タワーと真ん中の頼りない背中
And Tokyo Tower, with a slender back right in between.
サボり方とか 甘え方とか 逃げ方とか言い訳の仕方とか
How to slack off, how to depend on others, how to run away, how to make excuses...
やっと覚えて来た 身につけて来た 柔らかい頭
I've finally learned, acquired a flexible mind.
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方 腹の据え方 良い年のこき方
How to act cool, how to get carried away, how to settle down, how to age gracefully,
脂の乗った 濁った目をした だらし無かった
In my prime, with muddy eyes, I was so sloppy.
嫌われ方や 慕われ方や 叱り方とか 綺麗なぶつかり方
How to be hated, how to be loved, how to scold, how to clash gracefully...
覚えた事が山のようにある
I have a mountain of things I've learned.
のびしろしか無いわ
There's nothing but room to grow!
俺達まだのびしろしかないわ
We still have nothing but room to grow!
くだんない話と
Silly conversations,
うざったい貴様と
and an annoying fellow like you,
なみなみの日々に 注がれてく
Being poured into ordinary days,
怠いが溢れ出していく
A sense of sluggishness overflows.
飯がまだ届かない
The food hasn't arrived yet,
仕事は片付かない
Work isn't getting finished,
うだつの上がらない 毎日にため息ばかり
Sighing every day in an unproductive life.
でまたド派手にすっころび
And then taking a spectacular fall again,
洗い立てのシャツにこぼすコーヒー
Spilling coffee on a freshly washed shirt,
前のめり その姿勢だけは褒めて良し
Leaning forward—at least praise that attitude!
肩落とす並木通り 増えた柄と差し色に
Walking down the tree-lined avenue with slumped shoulders, with added patterns and accent colors.
嗚呼…本当嫌なる毎日だ
Ah... these days are truly depressing.
やりたくないことやったって
Even if I do things I don't want to do,
嫌々早起きしたって
Even if I reluctantly wake up early,
その分素敵な何かが 訪れるとかそんなわけでもないのにさ
It doesn't mean something wonderful will come my way, and yet...
今日にもまた頑張っちゃうよな
Here I am trying hard again today.
がむしゃら以外知らないから
Because I don't know any other way than reckless effort.
不器用で意地張りで 馬鹿真面目な僕らに幸あれ
May happiness come to us clumsy, stubborn, stupidly honest ones.
重くなってきた荷物をちょっと置いて立ち止まり
Setting down the heavy luggage for a moment to pause,
昨日の事なんぞ忘れちまえば同じ
Forgetting yesterday's troubles makes no difference anyway.
浴びるdaylight 羽根伸ばし
Basking in the daylight, stretching my wings,
それか月夜にこっそりと吐き出してしまえば良い
Or secretly venting it all out under the moonlit night.
でもその前にアレとコレの話
But before that, let's talk about this and that.
その為にはまずはソレを片して
For that to happen, first clean that up!
っで今何時？ いやその前に
Wait, what time is it now? No, before that...
今日もなんだかんだ騒がしい毎度あり
Today is noisy one way or another again, thanks as always!
1ヶ月くらい何にも 考えずだらだらしていたいな
I want to laze around for about a month without thinking of anything,
ゆっくり休んで遊んで眠っていたいな
Rest comfortably, play, and just sleep...
って思う日もあるけれど
There are days when I think like that, but...
やっとここまで来たんだよ
We've finally made it this far,
ここじゃ終われないんだよ
We can't end it here!
辛いきついもいつかは 笑い話にできると信じてるんだほら
Believing that all the pain and hardship will become a laughing matter someday, see?
今日もまた頑張っちゃうからさ
I'll work hard again today,
がむしゃらに愛を歌うからさ
Sing love recklessly!
目一杯吸い込んだ空気
Taking a deep breath of air,
嗚呼 本当素晴らしい毎日だ
Ah, what a truly wonderful everyday life!
やりたくないことやったって
Even if I do things I don't want to do,
嫌々早起きしたって
Even if I reluctantly wake up early,
ほんの少しの幸せに
Just touching a tiny bit of happiness...
触れるだけで全部全部ありに思えるんだ
...makes everything feel totally worth it!
明日もまた頑張ってみようか
Shall we try our best again tomorrow?
がむしゃらに生きていくんだ
Living recklessly forward!
不器用で意地張りで 馬鹿真面目な僕らに幸あれ
May happiness come to us clumsy, stubborn, stupidly honest ones.
do my thing do your thing 肩の力を抜いて柔軟に
Do my thing, do your thing, relax your shoulders and stay flexible.
again do my thing do your thing あと1ミリ背伸び
Again, do my thing, do your thing, stretching just 1mm further.
嗚呼 本当嫌になっちゃうよな
Ah, it truly gets frustrating, doesn't it?
それでも今を生きている
Even so, we live in the present.
不器用で意地張りで 馬鹿真面目なあなたに幸あれ
May happiness come to you, clumsy, stubborn, and stupidly honest.
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
A reasonable level of completion + a transparent imitation
あいつになりたくてもがいても
Even if you struggle wanting to become like them,
底なし沼のように沈んでくよ
You'll just sink like in a bottomless swamp.
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
A reasonable level of completion + a transparent imitation
NickelBurnして火つけて
Spark a NickelBurn and light the fire,
君の心に落とすimagination
Dropping imagination right into your heart.
ギリギリでフライできず地獄送りさ
Just barely missing the flight and sent straight to hell.
君が飛べなかった理由を一つ教えてやろうか
Shall I tell you one reason why you couldn't fly?
それは目の前のプロップスに心揺らぎ近道した結果
It's because your heart swayed for immediate props and you took a shortcut,
誰かの後をつつけてるだけだったからさ
All because you were just following in someone else's footsteps.
未だわからないか最初は気づいてた
Still don't get it? You noticed at the start,
知らぬふりして自分の道だと言い聞かせた
But pretended not to know and convinced yourself it was your own path.
他は騙せないオリジナルを奏でないと
You can't fool others unless you play something original,
過去の自分に足を引っ張られて退場
Dragged down by your past self and forced off the stage.
俺とお前との差は遺伝子レベル
The difference between you and me is on a genetic level.
俺を狂わせた父祖父母には感謝してる
I'm grateful to my parents and grandparents who drove me crazy,
さらに磨き上げた自分自身にも感謝してる
And I'm grateful to myself for honing it even further.
なのになんかしてる君 差が離れてくうちに
Yet you're doing whatever you do, and as the gap widens,
絶望を感じどうせラップやめるよ
You feel despair and you'll quit rapping anyway.
5年後いや4年後？これは余命宣告
5 years? No, 4 years? This is a terminal diagnosis.
現状に満足して威張ってんの？
Are you satisfied with the status quo and acting tough?
俺らは発展途上でもかっけえぞ
We're still developing, but we're cool as hell.
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
A reasonable level of completion + a transparent imitation
あいつになりたくてもがいても
Even if you struggle wanting to become like them,
底なし沼のように沈んでくよ
You'll just sink like in a bottomless swamp.
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
A reasonable level of completion + a transparent imitation
NickelBurnして火つけて
Spark a NickelBurn and light the fire,
君の心に落とすimagination
Dropping imagination right into your heart.
恋焦がれた男達と時をかけた女達
Men yearning for love and women who leaped through time,
上辺だけのお友達がお前の事甘やかす
Superficial friends pampering you all the time.
命削りぬらりくらり情熱だけ注ぐ歌詞
Whittling down life, slacking off, lyrics poured with passion,
現実に頬濡らす理想たちが雨降らす
Ideals raining down to wet your cheeks in reality.
あれもカスでこれもカスで俺の歌詞で振り向かす
That's trash, this is trash, I'll turn heads with my lyrics.
ムキになって無視してた知らぬうちに街を換う
Getting defensive and ignoring it, prowling through the town unnoticed.
体揺らし声を枯らしたって誰も聞いてない
Shaking your body and straining your voice, but nobody's listening.
導かれて聴いてみても耳は糸を引いてない
Even if guided to listen, your ears aren't drawn in at all.
今日と明日 明後日も白紙の中あさって
Today, tomorrow, the day after, searching through blank pages,
思想すらも曲がってる だけど顔は笑ってる
Even your mindset is twisted, but your face keeps smiling.
嘘だらけの肥溜めで のぼせるまで浸かって
Soaking in a cesspool of lies until you're dizzy,
空に祈り捧げたって 変えられるのは声だけ
Praying to the sky, but the only thing you can change is your voice.
何かあれば孤独気取り むしり取るかね
Pretending to be lonely whenever something happens, snatching up money.
指で擦りめくり 表あれば裏探すだけ
Rubbing and flipping with fingers, if there's a front, just looking for the back.
歯止め効かぬ無駄な愚痴も 全て愛で砕けて
Unstoppable useless complaints, all shattered by love,
もうこんな歌詞は書きたくない 全部お前のせい
I don't wanna write lyrics like this anymore, it's all your fault.
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
A reasonable level of completion + a transparent imitation
あいつになりたくてもがいても
Even if you struggle wanting to become like them,
底なし沼のように沈んでくよ
You'll just sink like in a bottomless swamp.
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
A reasonable level of completion + a transparent imitation
NickelBurnして火つけて
Spark a NickelBurn and light the fire,
君の心に落とすimagination
Dropping imagination right into your heart.
チチチ チーム友達
Ch-ch-ch Team Tomodachi
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi
俺たち何？ え？ チーム友達
What are we? Huh? Team Tomodachi
関西 関東 西 東 北 南
チーム友達
Kansai, Kanto, West, East, North, South
Team Tomodachi
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi
チーム チーム チーム友達
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team, Team, Team Tomodachi
Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi
俺たち何？ え？ チーム友達
What are we? Huh? Team Tomodachi
お好み焼き 食う鶴橋
腹いっぱい 飯は美味い
Eating okonomiyaki in Tsuruhashi
Full stomach, the food is delicious
一人じゃ寂しいし 電話きたり
かけ直した後すぐ行く会いに
It's lonely alone, getting a call
Calling back and going right over to meet up
T-E-A-M T-O-M-O-D-A-C-H-I
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi
チーム友達 混ざり合い
契り交わし 飲んでる酒
Team Tomodachi, hanging out together
Pledging bonds, drinking liquor
契り 契り 契り 契り
Pledge, pledge, pledge, pledge
契ろう 契ろう 契ろう 契ろう
Let's pledge, let's pledge, let's pledge, let's pledge
契り 契り 契り 契り
Pledge, pledge, pledge, pledge
契ろう 契ろう 契ろう 契ろう
Let's pledge, let's pledge, let's pledge, let's pledge
チチチ チーム友達 チーム友達
Ch-ch-ch Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi
俺たち何？ え？ チーム友達
What are we? Huh? Team Tomodachi
関西 関東 西 東 北 南
チーム友達
Kansai, Kanto, West, East, North, South
Team Tomodachi
チーム友達
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi
チーム チーム チーム友達
Team, team, Team Tomodachi
チーム友達
Team Tomodachi
俺たち何？え？ チーム友達
What are we? Huh? Team Tomodachi
チーム友達
Team Tomodachi
イエーイ！ ヨーヨーヨー！
Yay! Yo yo yo!
勝手に出てねえ、ヨー！
Don't just start on your own, yo!
メンチ切んの...ごめん。メンチ切んの顔よー！
Staring them down... sorry. Staring them down with that face, yo!
ガラが悪いよー！
Looking so rough and tough, yo!
ちょっとあの... / ちょっとね
Just a little... / A little bit, yeah.
帽子とかのせいでね、ちょっとヤカラっぽくなっちゃうけどね。
Because of these caps and stuff, we look a bit like hoodlums, but...
うん、カッコいいじゃん！ / カッコいいよね！
Yeah, it looks cool! / It is cool, right!
こんな格好いつかしてみたかったんだよー！
I've always wanted to try an outfit like this someday!
マジでこれバチくそ高いからこれ気をつけて。
Seriously, this stuff is crazy expensive, so be careful.
え、本当にね、今日来たら「これ用意してあるんで」って言われて、「え、これ何何これ？」って。
No, really, when I arrived today, they told me "We prepared this," and I was like "Eh? W-What is this?"
重たいでしょ？
It's heavy, right?
うん、重たい。でもカッコいい。
Yeah, heavy. But cool.
あのロック・リーみたいになってるから今、うちら。
We're like Rock Lee right now.
ロック・リー！
Rock Lee!
おもり付けてるからね今。
Because we're wearing heavy weights right now!
解き放たれたらもっと動けるけどね。 / そう、外したらね。
If we take them off, we'd be able to move way better. / Yeah, if we take them off.
いい感じになりますけど。
We'd be in super good shape, but...
え、でも、ころねさん、周年おめでとうございます！
Ah, but Korone-san, happy anniversary!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
7周年だよ、ころね。 / ねー！すごい！
It's your 7th anniversary, Korone. / Yeah! Amazing!
で、何気にね... ていうかみこちゃんの衣装見て？
And by the way... wait, look at Miko-chan's outfit!
これ誕生日で着てたやつね。
This is the one I wore for my birthday.
かわいい！え、後ろも見せて、後ろも。
Cute! Ah, show us the back too, show us the back.
ちょっと今回用意してくれたこの装飾に何かマッチしてて草なんですけど。 / めっちゃマッチしてます。
It kind of matches the decorations they set up for today, which is hilarious. / It matches so well!
え、でもそれで言うとさ、ころね、この衣装さ、ゲーマーズのイベントのやつじゃない？
Wait, speaking of which, Korone, isn't this outfit from the Gamers event?
超超超超超ゲーマーズの...衣装。かわいいじゃん！
It's the Cho-Cho-Cho-Cho-Cho Gamers... outfit. Isn't it cute?
みこちゃん、今日ね、これが初お披露目なんだ、この衣装の。
Miko-chan, today is actually the first time I'm showing off this outfit!
え！？
What?!
これで！？ / これで、「チーム友達」でちょっと初...
With this?! / With this! Unveiling it with "Team Tomodachi"...
初お披露目言っちゃったんですけれども。 / え、でもいいじゃん、いいじゃん！
I ended up unveiling it like this! / Ah, but that's fine, that's fine!
え、かわいい！ちょっと...ちょっと短くない？
It's cute! Wait... isn't it a bit short?
え、そうなの。ちょっとエッチじゃない？ / これめっちゃ短いんだよね。大丈夫かな？
Yeah, exactly. Isn't it a bit sexy? / This is super short, right? Is it okay?
あ、丸見え... こら！見せるのやめろ！
Ah, it's fully visible... Hey! Stop showing it off!
これ大丈夫かな？
Is this okay?
え、しかもね、これなんかさ、めっちゃ胸がパツパツって言われてて、これ。
And besides, people were saying my chest is squeezing into this real tight.
いや、なんかちょっとシワができちゃってるの、パツパツで。弾け飛びそうだよね、なんか。
Yeah, like there's wrinkles forming from being so tight. It looks like it's gonna burst open!
多分ね、サイズが合ってないんだと思う。
I think the size just doesn't fit me right.
ああ、でもそのくらいがね、良いですからね。
Ah, but that level of tightness is good!
え、じゃ写真撮ろうよ、写真。 / 写真撮りたい！
Hey, let's take a picture then, a picture. / I wanna take a picture!
ちょっとアップ目撮りたいんだよな。あ、いいね。うん。
I wanna take a close-up one. Ah, nice. Yeah.
じゃ、しゃがもうよ。 / しゃがむか。
Then let's crouch down. / Crouch down, huh?
ヨー！ / ヨー！ / あ、いいじゃん！
Yo! / Yo! / Ah, nice!
ヨーヨー！ スパイダーマンみたいなポーズ。
Yo yo! A pose like Spider-Man!
ヨー！ヨー！ / え、じゃサングラスもさ、取ってさ...
Yo! Yo! / Wait, then let's take off our sunglasses too and...
あ、取るからね。うん。 / よいしょ、よいしょ。
Ah, taking them off, okay. / Up we go, up we go.
待ってね、みんなね。 / よいしょ。
Wait a second, everyone. / Up we go.
行くよー！ せーの！
Here we go! Ready, set...
はい！ あ、取れた取れた取れた！
Okay! Ah, took them off, took them off!
え、アップ目取れる？ / アップ目で取りたい。イエーイ！
Can you get a close-up? / I wanna take it close-up. Yay!
あ、じゃちょっとカメラをね、いただきましてね。あ、どう？
Ah, then let's get the camera over here. Ah, how's this?
イエーイ！ ヨー！
Yay! Yo!
取れてる？ チーム友達！
Did you get it? Team Tomodachi!
どこ歌ってんねん！
What part are you singing?!
え、でもさ、この曲さ、選んでくれたの嬉しかったよ。
Hey, but I was so happy you chose this song.
やっぱ「チーム友達」っていうぐらいの歌だから、友達と歌いたくて。
Since the song is literally titled "Team Tomodachi", I wanted to sing it with a friend.
だから誰でもよかったんだけど、別に。友達だからみんな。
So honestly, anyone would've been fine, really. Everyone's a friend.
おい！嘘嘘嘘！
Hey! Lie, lie, lie!
特に！特にみこみこと歌いたかった！
Especially! I especially wanted to sing it with Miko-miko!
ありがと。
Thank you.
「チーム友達」だから当たり前じゃん。チーム友達、イエーイ！
Because we're "Team Tomodachi", of course! Team Tomodachi, yay!
え、でもそろそろね、次の曲なんじゃないですか？
Hey, but isn't it about time for the next song?
あ、そう。もうちょっとね、もうちょっとだけ続くんじゃよなんだけど。
Ah, right. There's still "a little bit more to go", though.
うん、え、次どんな感じなの？
Yeah, so what's the next one like?
え、次はね、パンツですね。
Well, next is... PANTS.
え？
Eh?
パンツ。
PANTS.
パンツ？ 恥ずかしい。
PANTS? Embarrassing...
やめて、撮らないで。撮らないで！ パンツって、この、履いてるパンツってこと？
Stop, don't film! Don't film! By PANTS, you mean the... underwear we're wearing?
え、みこさん履いてないの？
Eh, Miko-san, aren't you wearing any?
え？
Eh?
みこさん履いてないの？パンツ。
Miko-san, aren't you wearing any? Underwear.
安心してください、履いてますよ！
Don't worry, I'm wearing them!
履いてる？ あ、よかったじゃあ。
You are? Ah, good then.
え、ころねはまだこれからなのよ、パンツ。
Eh, Korone's is still up next, PANTS.
え、え？履いてないってこと？
Eh, wait? Does that mean you're not wearing any?
ころねはちょっとこれからなの。だから、ごめん、みこみこ、これからだから、ころねパンツ。
Korone's is coming up next. So, sorry Miko-miko, it's next, Korone's PANTS.
パ、パンツ...？
P-PANTS...?
チャーニー ヨー
Johnny, yo
Don't worry, Don't flex / Don't worry, Don't flex
Don't worry, Be naked / 但し履け PANTS
Don't worry, Be naked / But wear it, PANTS
Animal naked / Nature naked / People naked / 但し履け PANTS
Animal naked / Nature naked / People naked / But wear it, PANTS
Don't worry, Don't flex / Don't worry, Don't flex
Don't worry, Be naked / 但し履け PANTS
Don't worry, Be naked / But wear it, PANTS
No pants, No life / No pants, No steam / No pants, No night / 但し履け PANTS
No pants, No life / No pants, No steam / No pants, No night / But wear it, PANTS
キッキ ネキッ キン ネキッ キン / キッキ ネキッ キッキ ネキッ キン ネキッ キン
Kick kick naked King, Naked King / Kick kick naked, Kick kick naked King, Naked King
Kin Naked Kin Naked Kin...
Don't worry, don't flex, don't worry, don't flex
Don't worry, be naked
But wearing PANTS!
Animal Naked Nature Naked People Naked But wearing PANTS!
Don't worry, don't flex, don't worry, don't flex
Don't worry, be naked But wearing PANTS!
You say naked, I say NO! I say naked, you say NO!
You say wearing, I say PANTS! I say wearing, you say PANTS!
Kin Naked Kin Naked Kin...
HEY!
Simon push, Simon push
I'm wearing PANTS, but I can pose naked! HEY!
マフィオーサ
[Title: Mafiosa]
Ah listen up
キラッと光る犬歯がお似合いの口が物語る
The mouth suited for flashing canine teeth tells a story
リリカルがもくもくと充満し織り成すスモーキーなストーリー
Lyrical rhymes swell and fill the air, weaving a smoky story
Let me see...
不確かな平和と確かな不安を護い彷徨う
Wandering through uncertain peace and certain anxiety
お描いじゃないことに恐れ慄く
Trembling in fear at what can't be controlled
十色の価値観 騒ぐラジカル 何がはじまる？
Ten different values, rowdy radicals, what's about to start?
不器用な生き様に心痛む (Ahh)
A clumsy way of life breaks my heart
I wonder why 理性を欠いたサバイブ 願っても願ってもなくならない
I wonder why, a survival devoid of reason won't disappear no matter how much I wish
I wonder why 危険度ハイなマイライフ Do it again, do it again
I wonder why, my high-risk life, do it again, do it again
Chase, chase, Where is my utopia こじ開ける扉 Viva 現状打破なら飛び乗りな
Chase, chase, where is my utopia? Prying open the door, viva, if breaking the status quo, jump on in
くしゃくしゃの紙くずに傷ついたハート重ねる しわむいたまま時を刻む（踊れ）
Stacking a wounded heart onto crumpled scrap paper, ticking through time while wrinkled (Dance)
多数のお目目から逃げた Back in the day ひた隠している ファンキーなヘッド
Fleeing from countless eyes back in the day, keeping this funky head hidden away
個性の延長線上にあるギフトも誰かにとってはバグみたい
Even a gift on the extension of individuality seems like a glitch to someone else
伏し目を逸らし 行く当てもない
Averting downcast eyes, with nowhere left to go
現状 感情 洗浄 出来ず立ち往生
Unable to wash away the current state and emotions, stuck at a standstill
抱いても泣いても足掻いても Fall...
Whether embracing, crying, or struggling... Fall...
Uhh 放浪 噛み締め 揺蕩う
Uhh, savoring the wandering, drifting along
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far 一歩前に踏み出す アニマル
Hey don't panic, go too far far far, stepping one pace forward, animal
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far
一丁前に 超前に 超前に (Straight out)
Like a boss, way ahead, way ahead (Straight out)
WIP aww WIP aww WIP aww aww aww
Critical Critical Criti Criti
Don't panic, Go too far far far
暗闇が Take over さながら予定調和
Darkness takes over, just like pre-established harmony
覚えたての絶望にほだされ見る見る間に裏目を出す
Swayed by newly learned despair, backfiring in the blink of an eye
手招く反逆のアイコン 一抹の不安抱くも邂逅
Beckoning icon of rebellion, meeting despite harboring a tinge of anxiety
平和ボケした連中を尻目に日陰通り歩けば Dope Dope Dope
Ignoring the peace-dulled crowd, walking through the shadows is dope dope dope
What a uhmm...
山積みトラブルに追われ追われ多忙
Chased and overwhelmed by a mountain of trouble, so busy
やさぐれバローに花向け発砲 (BANG!)
Firing a parting shot at a jaded barrow (BANG!)
Bang ba bang ba bang ba ぶち抜く不条理 ヘッドばんばん
Bang ba bang ba bang ba, blasting through absurdity, head banging
出る杭打つのに必死なプライド 塗れのエネミーに見舞う超ヤバイもん
Pride desperate to hammer down outstanders, unleashing something insane on pride-soaked enemies
狂った情情で冷え切った体温 上げるこのエナジーは文字通りデザイン
Body temperature chilled by crazy emotions, raising this energy literally by design
運命捻じ曲げるトリガー 着火する煙たい Dogs の通りだ (Gooo!)
Trigger to twist fate, igniting just like the smoky dogs (Gooo!)
皆誰もがスペシャルな存在とのこと忘れた結果
As a result of everyone forgetting that every single person is special
自分と違う箇所否定して笑っぱねる それこそ欠陥
Denying and rejecting whatever differs from themselves, that is the true flaw
たくさんの矛盾と向き合い続けて尚 一向になくならない愚かなる (Battle)
Continuing to face countless contradictions, yet this foolish battle never disappears
悲愴 失踪 闘争 Never never end
Grief, disappearance, struggle, never never end
散らばる Hollow
Scattering hollow
ぎらり剥き出しの牙と思惑が絡み合う
Glaring, bared fangs and secret motives intertwine
消灯 深い夜と歌う
Lights out, singing with the deep night
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far
一歩前に踏み出す アニマル (aww)
Stepping one pace forward, animal (aww)
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far
一丁前に 超前に 超前に (Straight out)
Like a boss, way ahead, way ahead (Straight out)
WIP aww WIP aww WIP aww aww aww
Critical Critical Criti Criti
Don't panic, Go too far far far
Work like a dog 只管に磨いたジョブ
Work like a dog, a job honed earnestly
ぼんやり未来が望遠鏡に浮かんだ今日
Today a hazy future floated into the telescope
いつかのオメルタもスーベニア
Someday's omertà will also be a souvenir
凍り付いた心を溶かす My whereabouts
Melting a frozen heart, my whereabouts
マフィオーサ 祝砲を放つ (Yeah)
Mafiosa firing a celebratory salute (Yeah)
アイネ・クライネ・ナハトムジーク ぐずついた顔はグッバイ
Eine kleine Nachtmusik, goodbye to sullen faces
マフィオーサ 祝福の歌 (Yeah)
Mafiosa song of blessing (Yeah)
ようやく見つけた 掛け替えのない居場所
Finally found an irreplaceable place to belong
Say hoo! ほら一緒に踊ろう
Say hoo! Come on, let me dance with you
Say hoo! また一緒に踊ろう
Say hoo! Let's dance together again
Say hoo! ずっと一緒に踊ろう
Say hoo! Let's dance together forever
ようやく気付けた ふたつとない居場所
Finally realized, a one and only place to belong
居場所ー！
A place to belong!
みんな！マフィオーザ ライブ初披露、どうだったー？
Everyone! How was the live premiere of Mafiosa?
ちょっとパンツとマフィオーザで2曲続けてだったんですけど
I performed two songs in a row, "PUNPZ" and "Mafiosa",
このねパンツっていう曲めちゃめちゃ好きで、ずっと暇の時めちゃめちゃ聴いてたので、今回歌えて嬉しいのと
and I really love "PUNPZ". I used to listen to it all the time, so I was super happy to perform it today,
ころねすきーにね、ピンクのパンツを履いて踊ってもらえたのがすごく楽しかったので、みんな踊ってくれてありがとー！
and seeing Koronesuki wearing pink undies and dancing along was so much fun! Thank you all for dancing!
はい。でね、今回マフィオーザのライブ初お披露目をしたくて、全部ねラップ曲でまとめてみたんですけど、どうだったかな？
Alright. And since I wanted to do a live debut of "Mafiosa", I put together a whole setlist of rap songs. How was it?
ちょっと初めての試みだったから、準備段階から今日に至るまでめちゃドッキドキで、みんな楽しんでくれるかなとか思ってたんだけど
Since it was a new challenge for me, I was so nervous from the prep stage all the way until today, wondering if everyone would enjoy it.
だからね、みんなが楽しんでノリノリになってくれてたら嬉しいなと思います！
So if you all enjoyed it and got into the groove, that makes me super happy!
でね、原曲知らないよっていう方がね、結構いると思うんですけど...結構はいないか、いると思うんですけど
Also, I think there might be quite a few people who don't know the original songs... well, maybe not "quite a few", but some!
もしね、そういう方はぜひ、めちゃめちゃかっこいいので全部の曲、原曲ぜひ聴いてみてください！
If so, please check out the originals! Every single song is so cool!
あ、最後に歌ったマフィオーザもですね、めちゃめちゃ原曲かっこいいので、ぜひみんな聴いてねー！
Ah, and "Mafiosa" that I sang at the end is super cool in its original version too, so definitely check it out!
はい！ということで、今回もあります！周年グッズです！こちらー！
Alright! With that said, we have them again this time! Anniversary merch! Here they are!
急に来る！はい！
Coming out of nowhere! Yes!
今回はですね、なんと...うすた京介先生に書き下ろしていただきましたー！ありがとうございます！
And this time, amazingly... Usuta Kyosuke-sensei drew illustrations for us! Thank you so much!
1つずつ見ていきますかね
Shall we take a look at them one by one?
最初はいですね、YB-2！久しぶりに出ました。うちのブランドYB-2です。YB-2のうすた先生バージョンのね、パーカーです！
First up, YB-2! It's been a while. Our brand YB-2. It's the YB-2 Usuta-sensei version hoodie!
裏面にイラストが来る感じですね。で胸元にYB-2って入ってて、腕にね、Koroneのモチーフの骨が入っております。これめちゃめちゃかっこいいと思うのでね、お楽しみにー！
The illustration is printed on the back. It has "YB-2" on the chest, and Korone's bone motif on the sleeves. I think this looks super cool, so look forward to it!
続いてこちら！こちらはですね、パーカーと同じイラストのサコッシュです
Next up is this! This is a sacoche featuring the same illustration as the hoodie.
結構ね、EXPOとかフェスとか、みんなのねイベントとかに来る時にサコッシュ使ってる人結構いたなと思って、Koroneもサコッシュ出したい！っていうことでサコッシュ出しました！みんなぜひ使ってください！
I noticed a lot of people using sacoches when coming to events like EXPO or festivals, so I wanted to make one too! So here it is! Please make good use of it!
続いてこちら！こちらはですね...ごめんなさいね。RAP DOGキャップ！
Next is this! This is... sorry. The RAP DOG Cap!
こちらはですね、Hikosan先生のデザインで出させていただきました！ありがとうございます！
This was designed by Hikosan-sensei! Thank you so much!
ここにね、Koroneの骨がクロスしてて、横にまたこれYB-2です。これYB-2なのでね、パーカーとサコッシュと帽子、全部YB-2のブランドでございます！よろしくお願いします！
Korone's bones cross here on the front, and on the side, it's YB-2 again! So the hoodie, sacoche, and cap are all under the YB-2 brand! Check them out!
はい、次！
Alright, next!
これはYB-2じゃない Koroneのランダムラバーストラップ！こちらね、フカヒレママに書き下ろしてもらいました！ママありがとー！
"This Isn't YB-2: Korone's Random Rubber Strap"! These were illustrated by Fukahire-mama! Thank you, Mama!
こちらね、4種類ランダムで。で今回ね、ラップの曲が多かったということで、ラップをしてるね、Koroneのイラストもありますので、ぜひ皆さん全種類目指してよかったら買ってみてください！
There are 4 random types. And since there were a lot of rap songs this time, there's also an illustration of Korone rapping! So please try to collect them all!
通常衣装と、YB-2のジャンプスーツと、グッドドッグ衣装と、ラッパー衣装ですね！よかったらはい、こちらもご検討ください！
There's the standard costume, YB-2 jumpsuit, good dog costume, and rapper costume! Please consider getting these too!
そしてフルセットの購入特典は、うすた先生書き下ろしのですね、ポストカード！数量限定版もありますけれど、めちゃめちゃ用意しておりますので、急がないで大丈夫です！マジで結構用意したので、ゆっくりご購入ください！
And the bonus for buying the full set is a postcard with a new illustration by Usuta-sensei! There's a limited quantity version too, but we prepared a ton of them, so no need to rush! Really, take your time!
はい！で通常バージョンはね、箔押しの複製サイン入りとなっております！
Yes! And the standard version comes with a foil-stamped printed signature!
はい！ということで、今回のライブもみんな！たくさん見てくれてありがとうございましたー！
Alright! So thank you so much to everyone who watched today's live stream!
以上！LAZY DOG NIGHTでしたー！みんな本当いつもありがとねー！また会おう！またねー！
That was LAZY DOG NIGHT! Thank you all so much as always! Let's meet again! Bye-bye!
Lazy Dog Night